{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In case of Raymond pile", "opta": "lengths vary from 6 m to 12 m", "optb": "diameter of top of piles varies from 40 cm to 60 cm", "optc": "diameter of pile at bottom varies from 20 cm to 28 cm", "optd": "thickness of outer shell depends upon pile diameter", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Queen closer may be placed", "opta": "in header course", "optb": "in stretcher course", "optc": "in header course next to first brick", "optd": "in stretcher course next to first brick", "opte": "in any position.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dado is usually provided in", "opta": "dinning halls", "optb": "bath rooms", "optc": "living rooms", "optd": "verandah", "opte": "roofs.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The foundation in which a cantilever beam is provided to join two footings, is known as", "opta": "strip footing", "optb": "strap footing", "optc": "combined footing", "optd": "raft footing", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The foundations are placed below ground level, to increase", "opta": "strength", "optb": "workability", "optc": "stability of structure", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stud(s) of a common wooden partition", "opta": "are vertical wooden members", "optb": "is the upper horizontal wooden member", "optc": "is the lower horizontal wooden member", "optd": "are the intermediate horizontal wooden members.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following :", "opta": "inclined borings are made for taking samples under existing structures", "optb": "inclined borings are occasionally used instead of vertical holes.", "optc": "the spacing of inclined borings is kept such that one bore hole is vertically above the bottom of an adjacent bore hole.", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the commonly adopted geophysical method in civil engineering from the following :", "opta": "the seisomic method", "optb": "electrical resistivity method", "optc": "gravitational method", "optd": "magnetic method", "opte": "both (a) and (b) of the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To ensure that supporting area of an offset footing of a boundary wall is fully compressive, the C.G. of load must act", "opta": "at the centre of the base", "optb": "within the middle third of the base", "optc": "within the middle fifth of the base", "optd": "neither (a), (b) nor (c).", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 9 cm x 9 cm side of a brick as seen in the wall face, is generally known as", "opta": "stretcher", "optb": "face", "optc": "front", "optd": "header", "opte": "side.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The taper of precast concrete pile should not be more than", "opta": "1 cm per metre length", "optb": "2 cm per metre length", "optc": "4 cm per metre length", "optd": "5 cm per metre length.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The under surface of an arch, is called", "opta": "soffit", "optb": "intrados", "optc": "haunch", "optd": "back.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The raft slab is projected beyond the outer walls of the structure by", "opta": "5 to 10 cm", "optb": "15 to 20 cm", "optc": "25 to 30 cm", "optd": "30 to 45 cm", "opte": "60 cm.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of making the back ground rough, before plastering, is", "opta": "dubbing", "optb": "hacking", "optc": "blistering", "optd": "peeling.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Black cotton soil is unsuitable for foundations because its", "opta": "bearing capacity is low", "optb": "permeability is uncertain", "optc": "particles are cohesive", "optd": "property to undergo a volumetric change due to variation of moisture content.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The loose pockets in soil mass can be bridged safely by providing a raft foundation provided the soft area is smaller than", "opta": "the column spacing", "optb": "one-third the column spacing", "optc": "half the column spacing", "optd": "three-fourth the column spacing", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The portion of a brick cut across the width, is called", "opta": "closer", "optb": "half brick", "optc": "bed", "optd": "bat.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The concrete slump recommended for beams and slabs ; is", "opta": "25 to 50 mm", "optb": "25 to 75 mm", "optc": "30 to 125 mm", "optd": "50 to 100 mm", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The member which is placed horizontally to support common rafter of a sloping roof, is", "opta": "purlin", "optb": "cleat", "optc": "batten", "optd": "strut.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "Louvered door is generally provided in bath rooms", "optb": "Flush  door  is  generally  provided   in dinning room", "optc": "Revolving door is generally provided in cinema halls", "optd": "Sliding door is generally provided in show rooms", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Grillage foundation", "opta": "is used to transfer heavy structural loads from steel columns to a soil having low bearing capacity", "optb": "is light and economical", "optc": "does not require deep cutting as the required base area with required pressure intensity is obtained at a shallow depth", "optd": "is constructed by rolled steel joists (R.S.J.) placed in single or double tier", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The exterior angle between outer faces of a wall, is known as", "opta": "turn", "optb": "junction", "optc": "quion", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In jack arch floor, the rise is kept", "opta": "1/6th of the span", "optb": "1/8th of the span", "optc": "1/10th of the span", "optd": "1/12th of the span", "opte": "1/15th of the span.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "While designing a stair, the product of rise and going is approximately kept equal to", "opta": "350", "optb": "420", "optc": "450", "optd": "500", "opte": "600.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For constructing a terrazo floor. Pick up the incorrect statement from the following :", "opta": "a base course is prepared as in cement concrete flooring", "optb": "a 32 mm thick layer of cement concrete (1 : 2 : 4) is laid on the base course and the surface is made smooth by trowelling", "optc": "glass strips are driven into the layer according to the pattern required", "optd": "after final grinding is over, oxalic acid mixed with water is spread over and rubbed hard with soft material", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The entrained concrete is used in lining walls and roofs for making", "opta": "heat insulated", "optb": "sound insulated", "optc": "neither (a) nor (b)", "optd": "both (a) and (b).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The pile which is provided with a bulb filled with concrete at its lower end, is known as", "opta": "Simplex pile", "optb": "Mac-Arthur pile", "optc": "Raymond pile", "optd": "Franki pile", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In case of multi-storeyed buildings, the forms to be removed first are", "opta": "sides of beams and girders", "optb": "column forms", "optc": "bottom of beams and girders", "optd": "all the above at the same time.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For providing a raft foundation, the following activities are involved ramming the foundation bedexcavation of the soil upto required depthlaying the reinforcement over the foundation bedcuring the cement concrete placed over reinforcementpouring the cement concrete over the reinforcement. The correct sequence is", "opta": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5", "optb": "5, 4, 3, 2, 1", "optc": "2, 1, 3, 5, 4", "optd": "3, 2, 5, 1, 4.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum permissible deflection of a timber beam supporting a roof, is", "opta": "L/100", "optb": "L/150", "optc": "L/260", "optd": "L/360", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The angular steps used for changing direction of the stairs, are called", "opta": "round steps", "optb": "angular steps", "optc": "winders", "optd": "radial steps", "opte": "circular steps.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During percussion drilling", "opta": "ground water observations are hindered due to entry of the slurry in the soil below the bottom of the hole", "optb": "caving or mixing of strata are caused in soft soils or cohesionless soils", "optc": "the soil to a considerable depth below the bottom of the hole gets disturbed", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In English garden wall bond", "opta": "one course of headers to three or five course of stretchers", "optb": "queen closer in provided in each heading course", "optc": "the middle course of stretchers is started with a header to give proper vertical joints", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A projecting piece usually provided to support a truss, is", "opta": "cornice", "optb": "coping", "optc": "frieze", "optd": "lintal.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The line of intersection of the surfaces of a sloping roof forming an external angle exceeding 180\u00b0, is", "opta": "ridge", "optb": "hip", "optc": "valley", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A solid core of rock is formed in side the cylinder in the case of", "opta": "auger boring", "optb": "percussion drilling", "optc": "diamond drilling", "optd": "wash boring.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The single stage well point system of dewatering an excavation can be used if the depth of excavation does not exceed", "opta": "5 m", "optb": "10 m", "optc": "15 m", "optd": "20 m", "opte": "25 m.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The piece of a brick cut with its one corner equivalent to half the length and half the width of a full brick, is known as", "opta": "queen closer", "optb": "bevelled closer", "optc": "king closer", "optd": "half king closer.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The brick laid with its breadth parallel to the face of a wall, is known as", "opta": "header", "optb": "stretcher", "optc": "closer", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A wooden block hinged on post outside a door, is known", "opta": "cleat", "optb": "stop", "optc": "horn", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following :", "opta": "The function of foundation is to distribute the load of super structure over a large bearing area", "optb": "No  timbering is  required  for  shallow trenches", "optc": "Shallow foundations can be constructed on made-up soil", "optd": "Grillage   foundation   is   classified as a shallow foundation", "opte": "Black cotton soil is very good for foundation bed.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In horizontal D.P.C, thickness of cement concrete (1 : 2 : 4) is", "opta": "2 cm", "optb": "4 cm", "optc": "6 cm", "optd": "8 cm", "opte": "10 cm.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following factors is considered for the orientation of buildings :", "opta": "the direction of the prevailing winds in the area", "optb": "the exposure of the walls and roof of the buildings to the rays of sun", "optc": "the extent up to which the sunrays penetrate with the verandah.", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following :", "opta": "Cement is added to lime mortar to increase its hydraulic properties only", "optb": "Lime surkhi mortar is used for pointing the walls", "optc": "Lime should be slaked before preparing lime mortar", "optd": "High early strength concrete is generally used in cold weather.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following rocks is used for monumental buildings :", "opta": "granite", "optb": "marble", "optc": "sand stone", "optd": "slate.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Auger borings are not common", "opta": "in soils that require lateral support", "optb": "in cohesive soils", "optc": "in soft soils", "optd": "none of the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The form work from the underside of slabs, can be removed only after", "opta": "1 day", "optb": "4 days", "optc": "7 days", "optd": "14 days.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Arches in the form of masonry arcs struck from more than four centres, are called", "opta": "two curved arches", "optb": "gothic arches", "optc": "ogee arches", "optd": "drop gothic arches.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If (\u03c6) is the angle of repose of soil of weight w kg/m3, the horizontal pressure p at a depth of h metres per metre length of wall, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to Rankine's formula, minimum depth of foundations, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}